NAMRATA GANATRA

A MENSA member with ~11 years of experience in project management, strategic initiatives, international B2B sales, pre-sales and marketing. Highly passionate and driven, working with a customer obsessive mindset in a fast-paced environment. Extensive exposure of consensus-building with the Executive Management, successfully executing on strategic projects with an entrepreneurial spirit.

Work Experience

Telia, Stockholm, Sweden

Oct 2023 - Apr 2024

Project Lead – Business Process Improvement, BU B2B Enterprise Solutions
As part of the Customer Driven Change team, I have led a project aimed at reducing the on-boarding time of public and key customers by 30%. I collaborated with teams across Sales, Pre-sales, Project Managers and Implementation Coordinators to map the process, identify changes and lead them towards implementation. These changes will improve Telia's customer experience and competitiveness in the market, thereby resulting in financial gains and operational efficiency. This project also aligns with Telia's strategy to 'Shift to Digital', since upgrading online platforms are a part of project goals.

BuildSafe, Stockholm, Sweden

Aug 2019 - Apr 2020

Inside Sales and Marketing

I spearheaded the initiative to tap into new markets, presenting to Directors and Group Heads remotely, and automated various marketing activities.

Evalueserve, Delhi/Gurgaon, India

Sep 2007 – Aug 2014

Group Manager: Project Management, Strategy and Pre-Sales

I led various digitalization projects across Knowledge Management, HR, Training and Sales. My Pre-Sales Team of 20 analysts supported the global sales team with various customised activities. My team was spread across Romania, China, Chile and India, hence I worked closely with people of varied nationalities.

ICICI Bank, Kolkata, India

Jan 2007 – Aug 2007

Sales Manager

I led a team of 40, selling liability and insurance products to SMEs. My proactive and self-driven attitude was also recognized for identifying potentially fraudulent accounts, significantly reducing the bank's risk and exposure.

Max New York Life Insurance, Delhi/Gurgaon, India Jun 2005 – Dec 2006 Assistant Manager: Strategic Initiatives

I was creating and rolling out strategic initiatives with a direct revenue impact. Hiring summer interns to sell insurance was one of my main ideas piloted. I also evaluated potential business partnership for various alternate channels.

Education

SVA- Grundläggande & Gymnasium (Swedish language at KOMVUX) SFI (svenska för invandrare)	2018 - 2020 2014 - 2015
Management in Business Administration (MBA)	2003 - 2005
Management Development Institute, Gurgaon, India	
Bachelors in Commerce (Accountancy and Economics)	1999 - 2002
Calcutta University, Kolkata/Calcutta, India	
Bachelors in Information Technology (BIT)	1999 - 2002
Manipal Academy of Higher Education, India	

Awards

- Best Team
- Excellence in Leadership



Contact Details:

Ursviks Alle 49
174 66 Sundbyberg
Mobile: 076-432 1898
ganatranamrata@yahoo.com
linkedin.com/in/namrataganatra

Languages

English: Fluent/Native: 10/10

Swedish: Fluent: 8/10

Exposure

Business Analysis: 8/10

CRM: 7/10

Digitization 8/10

Sales: 7/10

Pre-Sales: 9/10 Marketing: 4/10

Computer Proficiency

MS Office (Word, Excel, PPT):

10/10

Google suites (Sheets, Docs,

Tableau: 3/10 SalesForce: 5/10 PipeDrive: 10/10

Slides): 10/10

SAP Analytics Cloud: 3/10

Soft Skills

- A natural and confident relationship builder
- Agile and flexible
- Proactive and action oriented
- Analytical and pragmatic
- Strong oral and written communication skills

References

• Can be provided upon request

A Business Manager with global experience!



As a highly motivated and experienced Business Manager with a track record of leading strategic projects and teams in diverse industries, I believe I am well-equipped to contribute positively to your organization. I have completed my Masters of Business Administration (MBA) in 2005, and speak fluent Swedish and native English!

A natural and confident relationship builder

At Telia, I have collaborated seamlessly with various teams including sales, presales, and the Customer Service Delivery organization for the B2B segment, building strong relationships all along.

At Evalueserve, I have led sales and pre-sales teams of 5-40 members, across countries and cultures, building strong relations with my team members and colleagues. The employment retention rate was higher than other teams in my department.

Testimonials from team members and managers attest to my unwavering dedication to both individual success and organizational growth.

Analytical and pragmatic

During my 11-year career, I have honed my skills in project management, strategic initiatives, sales, and marketing across various industries.

At Telia, I successfully worked in a complex project with a matrix structure, first identifying pieces of a puzzle, and then putting them together to map the existing process, identifying potential areas for improvement and leading them to the final stage of implementation, thus working end to end.

While in the role of Project Manager at Evalueserve, I have worked across several strategic projects for the Country Head's office, analyzing key issues and providing practical solutions that work for both the management and the teams alike.

Strong communication skills

My experience as a Business Manager in implementing important tools and bridging the gap between IT and Operations teams underscores my strong communication and stakeholder management skills. I have demonstrated the same at Telia too, when working across departments to gather information, get buy-ins from key stakeholders and begin the implementation of changes suggested by me. These projects have also honed my ability to collaborate and build consensus with diverse teams and executive management.